# MARK DITTMER

San Jose, CA | (408) 819-1146 | mdditt2000@yahoo.com | LinkedIn.com/in/mdditt2000/

## SR PRODUCT MANAGER

Product Leader at F5, owning strategy and roadmap for Automation, APIs, Kubernetes integration across F5 product. Strong IT leader, with multiple products and engineering teams in a fast-paced environment. Experience in leading cross-functional teams to plan, build, and launch IT projects, including APIs, Containers, Kubernetes/OpenShift, and other cloudnative applications and IT structures. Strong worth ethic and technical depth, with excellent problem solving, communication, and presentation skills.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

YouTube Channel – Kubernetes Ingress and Automation of BIG-IP <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MarkDittmer">https://www.youtube.com/@MarkDittmer</a> Automation and Orchestration | APIs | Containers and Kubernetes applications /

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

F5 Networks (San Jose, CA)

April 2022 – Present

#### **Sr Product Manager**

- Owner of F5 Automation and Orchestration. Defined the strategy for BIG-IP Automation and lifecycle management. Collaborate with an engineering team based in Seattle, San Jose and Hyderabad. Having a release every 6 weeks with new features based on customers engagements with account teams, GitHub and working with internal teams for the new F5 platform.
- Owner of Kubernetes integration across F5 product. Defined the roadmap, based on customer feedback, market
  direction and internal stakeholders. Continuing to deliver all the functionalities on time working closely with the
  engineering team and the business development partners.
- Abstract complex F5 configuration logic into community Kubernetes language, resulting in integration simplification.
- Practicing agile methiodides working with project team, defining, prioritizing, and finalizing customer requirements.
- Interface with customers and partner with enterprise cross-functional groups to collect market data, helping to make strategic business decisions.
- Interface with developers using Slack and GitHub to assist business partners with various clients, including Red Hat and Hashi Corporation, to articulate and drive integration activities.
- Support marketing and sales activities by providing training, collateral, blogging, and documenting and creating product demonstrations.
- Lead executive briefings for existing and potential clients.
- Active content creator for Automation Orchestration and Kubernetes. Always strategizing on how to expand my YouTube channel and community.

#### **Sr Technical Product Manager**

July 2016 – April 2022

- Provide technical knowledge to Product Management and engineering teams working on automation and Kubernetes integration, define, prioritize and groom the backlog, interact and be focal point for engineering.
- Interface with customers, partner and related functions in F5, to collect market requirements.
- Interface with other business units, cross functional teams and executive management
- Drive integration activities and solutions with external partners
- Support marketing and sales activities
- Interface with all levels of F5, including external customers, executive's global management, sales and external partners, at both a business and technology level.

CISCO (San Jose, CA) October 2000 – July 2016

#### **Solution Architect**

• Worked with Sales team to successfully win contract from incumbent provider, *HP*, to roll out thousands of Cisco UCS blade servers at GE locations throughout the country.

- Worked as on-site Cisco Consultant at Home Depot with Cloud team; strategized the appropriate cloud platform for e-commerce.
- Led a team of Architects for Cisco customers, migrated networking and Data Center infrastructure to Cisco from other providers.
- Migrated approximately 30 medical facilities and trauma centers across the United States
- Gathered business and technology requirements, determined architectural design, and formulated integration strategies and statements of work for external customers.
- Authored documentation for multiple Cisco Data Center technologies for migration and integration of client projects
- Worked as on-site Cisco Consultant and assisted in resolving escalations (problems caused by defects) by creating demos and acting as 'point of contact' for major companies; included GE, Shell Oil, CenturyLink, and Home Depot
- Built methodology for e-commerce cloud methodology.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelors Science, Information Technology | University of Phoenix (2005)